Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم المشرف شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
♪In the old house, a light breeze blows♪
♪في البيت القديم، تهب نسمة خفيفة♪
♪Carrying a wisp of floral fragrance♪
♪تحمل خصلة من العطر الزهري♪
♪You left in such haste, without hesitation♪
♪لقد غادرت على عجل، دون تردد♪
♪Before I could even feel the joy♪
♪قبل أن أشعر بالفرح♪
♪I dared not write a single word♪
♪لم أجرؤ على كتابة كلمة واحدة♪
♪Afraid it would give my heart away♪
♪أخشى أن يكشف قلبي♪
♪Leaving behind a foolish soul in loneliness♪
♪ترك وراءه روحًا حمقاء في الوحدة♪
♪The world grows old♪
♪العالم يشيخ♪
♪Time slips by like a blade♪
♪يمر الوقت مثل الشفرة♪
♪Through every day and night as I wait for the flowers to bloom♪
♪في كل يوم وليلة وأنا أنتظر الزهور لتتفتح♪
♪It feels as though a thousand years never passed♪
♪أشعر وكأن ألف عام لم تمر أبدًا♪
♪The wind lets petals fall into your palm♪
♪الريح تجعل البتلات تسقط في راحة يدك♪
♪Love makes us foolish, lost in endless memories♪
♪الحب يجعلنا حمقى، ضائعين في ذكريات لا نهاية لها♪
♪No one cares about our story♪
♪لا أحد يهتم بقصتنا♪
♪Slowly fading away♪
♪تتلاشى ببطء♪
♪Flowers bloom in snow, brief as life itself♪
♪تزهر الزهور في الثلج، قصيرة مثل الحياة نفسها♪
♪So many poems through the ages speak of♪
♪تتحدث العديد من القصائد عبر العصور عن♪
♪Love and hatred, partings and vows of the past♪
♪الحب والكراهية، الفراق وعهود الماضي♪
♪Had we never crossed paths in this lifetime♪
♪لو لم نلتقي قط في هذه الحياة♪
♪Nothing could separate us, even if we were oceans apart♪
♪لا شيء يمكن أن يفصلنا، حتى لو كنا بعيدين عن بعضنا البعض بالمحيطات♪
=The Princess Decree=
=مرسوم الأميرة=
=Episode 11=
=الحلقة 11=
Something just arrived from the Princess Royal's Residence.
لقد وصل شيء للتو من مقر إقامة الأميرة الملكية.
(A meeting at the Bookshop during the Hour of Wei)
(اجتماع في المكتبة خلال ساعة وي)
(Old Bookshop)
(المكتبة القديمة)
I didn't expect the favor Your Highness mentioned
لم أتوقع هذا الفضل الذي ذكره سموكم
to mean accompanying you on a shopping trip.
أن يعني مرافقتك في رحلة تسوق.
Why not?
ولم لا؟
A favor from Mr. Qingya isn't something one should turn down.
إن خدمة من السيد تشينغيا ليست شيئًا يجب على المرء أن يرفضه.
As it happens, I want to buy a painting as a gift.
كما يحدث، أريد شراء لوحة كهدية.
You're familiar with the arts.
أنت على دراية بالفنون.
You can help me choose.
يمكنك مساعدتي في الاختيار.
And buying it from Zhou can count as making it up to him.
وشرائه من تشو يمكن أن يعد تعويضًا له.
A gift?
هدية؟
May I ask who it's for, Your Highness?
هل يجوز لي أن أسأل لمن هذا، صاحب السمو؟
My mother.
والدتي.
To be more precise,
ولكي نكون أكثر دقة،
it's for a memorial offering.
إنه من أجل تقديم هدية تذكارية.
My mother loved calligraphy and paintings above all else.
كانت والدتي تحب الخط والرسم أكثر من أي شيء آخر.
Whenever she came across a fine piece,
كلما عثرت على قطعة جميلة،
she could stay up the entire night with it.
يمكنها البقاء مستيقظة طوال الليل معها.
She would spare no effort just to behold one.
لن تدخر جهدا لمجرد رؤية واحدة.
That year,
في تلك السنة،
I promised her
لقد وعدتها
that on her birthday,
أنه في عيد ميلادها،
I would give her the finest painting in the entire capital.
سأعطيها أفضل لوحة في العاصمة بأكملها.
But she was born in spring,
لكنها ولدت في الربيع،
and by the time winter snow fell, I had already left the capital.
وبحلول الوقت الذي تساقطت فيه الثلوج الشتوية، كنت قد غادرت العاصمة بالفعل.
In the end, I never made it back in time.
في النهاية، لم أتمكن من العودة إلى الزمن أبدًا.
After she passed,
بعد وفاتها،
her treasured paintings disappeared as well.
اختفت لوحاتها الثمينة أيضًا.
If she were watching from the afterlife,
لو كانت تراقب من الحياة الآخرة،
knowing her beloved collection was treated so poorly,
مع العلم أن مجموعتها المحبوبة تم التعامل معها بشكل سيء للغاية،
she would be heartbroken.
سوف تكون حزينة للغاية.
At that time, I was beyond the border.
في ذلك الوقت، كنت خارج الحدود.
I could barely protect myself,
بالكاد استطعت حماية نفسي،
let alone her paintings.
ناهيك عن لوحاتها.
Perhaps it wasn't as tragic as you think.
ربما لم يكن الأمر مأساويًا كما تعتقد.
Maybe the Consort had old acquaintances in the capital.
ربما كان للزوجة معارف قدامى في العاصمة.
They may have taken care of her belongings for her.
ربما قاموا برعاية ممتلكاتها نيابة عنها.
Is that so?
هل هذا صحيح؟
Even if you only said it to comfort me, thank you.
حتى لو قلت ذلك فقط لتعزيتي، أشكرك.
I failed my mother in many ways.
لقد خذلت والدتي في كثير من النواحي.
So I hope this memorial offering can make up for it in some small part.
لذا آمل أن يكون هذا العرض التذكاري قادرًا على التعويض عن ذلك في جزء صغير.
Tell me,
أخبرني،
which painting is the best?
أية لوحة هي الأفضل؟
That one.
هذا.
Though painted with only a few strokes,
على الرغم من أنها رسمت بضربات قليلة فقط،
the light ink captures blossoms in full bloom.
يلتقط الحبر الخفيف الأزهار في إزهارها الكامل.
A gentle rain, white pear flowers.
مطر لطيف، وزهور الكمثرى البيضاء.
It looks delicate,
يبدو رقيقًا،
yet it is the first to bloom in the chill of spring.
ومع ذلك فهو أول من يزدهر في برد الربيع.
How fitting.
كم هو مناسب.
Pear blossoms were my mother's favorite.
كانت أزهار الكمثرى هي المفضلة لدى والدتي.
I believe
انا أؤمن
she would truly love this one.
إنها ستحب هذا حقًا.
Thank you, sir.
شكرا لك سيدي.
There is no need for thanks, Your Highness.
لا داعي للشكر يا صاحب السمو.
Demon girl, prepare to die.
فتاة الشيطان، استعدي للموت.
Leave one alive.
أترك واحدا على قيد الحياة.
Demon girl,
فتاة شيطانية
you deserve the worst death.
أنت تستحق أسوأ موت.
(Old Bookshop)
(المكتبة القديمة)
You're quite the devoted father.
أنت أب مخلص جدًا.
To save your daughter,
لإنقاذ ابنتك،
you even take on any job offered.
حتى أنك تقبل أي وظيفة تُعرض عليك.
How did you know?
كيف عرفت؟
You thought assassinating me might solve your urgent troubles.
لقد اعتقدت أن اغتيالي قد يحل مشاكلك العاجلة.
But if you die,
ولكن إذا مت،
who will protect your daughter?
من سيحمي ابنتك؟
Did you really believe
هل كنت تؤمن حقا
I would let her go?
هل سأسمح لها بالذهاب؟
Xiao Pingning,
شياو بينجنينج,
you monster!
يا وحش!
Why do you hate me so much?
لماذا تكرهني كثيرا؟
Speak.
يتكلم.
Ever since you returned,
منذ عودتك،
you've been colluding with Gan Sheng.
لقد كنت متواطئًا مع جان شنغ.
You've thrown the entire court into chaos.
لقد أدخلت المحكمة بأكملها في حالة من الفوضى.
Everyone fears the two of you.
الجميع يخاف منكما الاثنين.
Xiao Pingning,
شياو بينجنينج,
you are utterly unworthy of being the Princess Royal of Jing!
أنت لا تستحقين على الإطلاق أن تكوني الأميرة الملكية لجينغ!
Killing you
قتلك
would rid the people of a plague.
سوف يخلص الناس من الطاعون.
I have no regrets!
ليس لدي أي ندم!
You really do hate me to your very core.
أنت حقا تكرهني إلى أعماق قلبك.
It seems
يبدو أنه
I can only...
لا أستطيع إلا...
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Let you go.
دعك تذهب.
Why?
لماذا؟
You despise me,
أنت تحتقرني
yet I insist you owe me your life.
ولكنني أصر على أنك مدين لي بحياتك.
Remember this. From this day on,
تذكر هذا. من هذا اليوم فصاعدًا،
I am the one who saved you.
أنا الذي أنقذك.
Xiao Pingning, you...
شياو بينغ نينغ، أنت...
Enough. Let him go.
كفى. دعه يذهب.
He's an eyesore.
إنه قبيح المنظر.
Move.
يتحرك.
Your wound needs tending.
جرحك يحتاج إلى العناية.
I have medicine with me.
عندي دواء معي.
Forgive the intrusion.
سامحني على التطفل.
Your Highness let him go.
سموكم سمح له بالذهاب.
That was a brilliant move.
لقد كانت تلك خطوة رائعة.
You mean
هل تقصد
I was only putting on a show for you?
لقد كنت أعرض عليك فقط؟
And once you looked away,
وبمجرد أن تنظر بعيدا،
I would have him killed?
هل أريد قتله؟
Would you?
هل ستفعل ذلك؟
So that's truly how you see me.
إذن هذه هي الحقيقة التي تراني بها.
After all,
بعد كل شيء،
that's what everyone in this world believes.
هذا ما يعتقده الجميع في هذا العالم.
It's only natural.
إنه أمر طبيعي.
Judging from Your Highness's tone,
انطلاقا من نبرة صوت سموكم،
does that mean Your Highness's decision
هل يعني هذا قرار سموكم؟
had another reason behind it?
هل كان هناك سبب آخر وراء ذلك؟
You mean letting that man go?
هل تقصد ترك هذا الرجل يذهب؟
Every wrong has its perpetrator, every debt its owner.
لكل خطأ فاعله، ولكل دين صاحبه.
He was nothing more than an insignificant pawn.
لم يكن أكثر من مجرد بيدق تافه.
I, Xiao Pingning, have no interest in making things difficult for him.
أنا، شياو بينج نينج، ليس لدي أي مصلحة في جعل الأمور صعبة عليه.
Besides,
بجانب،
a child is innocent. Why involve him?
الطفل بريء. لماذا نتدخل؟
(And were Mrs. Liu and Zhao not innocent too?)
(وهل كانت السيدة ليو وتشاو بريئتين أيضًا؟)
But tell me, sir,
ولكن قل لي يا سيدي،
since you truly believe
لأنك تؤمن حقا
I am a demon who kills without blinking,
أنا شيطان يقتل دون أن يرمش،
then when I was in danger just now,
ثم عندما كنت في خطر للتو،
why did you step in to save me?
لماذا تدخلت لإنقاذي؟
It was an emergency.
لقد كانت حالة طارئة.
Saving someone is instinct.
إن إنقاذ شخص ما هو غريزة.
Even a stray cat or dog,
حتى القطة أو الكلب الضال،
I would still help.
سأستمر في المساعدة.
Let alone a living person.
فما بالك بشخص حي.
With a heart like yours,
مع قلب مثل قلبك،
not becoming a living Bodhisattva in some temple
عدم التحول إلى بوديساتفا حي في بعض المعابد
is truly a pity.
إنه أمر مؤسف حقا.
Still, thank you for today, sir.
مع ذلك، أشكرك على اليوم، سيدي.
When I make my offering for my mother's memorial,
عندما أقدم قرباني لذكرى والدتي،
I will tell her about you.
سأخبرها عنك.
Heaven above,
السماء فوق
I pray you
أدعو لك
grant my mentor's family peace in the afterlife
امنح عائلة مرشدي السلام في الحياة الآخرة
and guide them to the Pure Land.
وهديهم إلى الأرض الطاهرة.
Mr. Liu,
السيد ليو،
I think I may have made a mistake.
أعتقد أنني ربما ارتكبت خطأ.
Or perhaps
أو ربما
I made that mistake a year ago.
لقد ارتكبت هذا الخطأ منذ عام.
Because
لأن
you were the one who saved my life.
لقد كنت الشخص الذي أنقذ حياتي.
My play saved Xiao Pingning,
لقد أنقذت مسرحيتي شياو بينج نينغ.
yet Xiao Pingning killed you.
ولكن شياو بينج نينغ قتلك.
I have always understood,
لقد فهمت دائما،
that in life,
أن في الحياة،
no one can escape the consequences of their actions.
لا أحد يستطيع الهروب من عواقب أفعاله.
But I never imagined,
ولكنني لم أتخيل ذلك أبدًا،
that the retribution would fall upon you.
أن يقع عليكم العقاب .
If a life must be exchanged for a life,
إذا كان لا بد من تبادل حياة بحياة أخرى،
why couldn't the one to die be me?
لماذا لا أكون أنا من يموت؟
Perhaps
ربما
this is retribution indeed.
وهذا هو الجزاء حقا.
Retribution for the fact that
الانتقام من حقيقة أن
I still harbored foolish hopes about her.
لا أزال أحمل آمالا سخيفة بشأنها.
Even today, I wavered again.
وحتى اليوم، ترددت مرة أخرى.
I nearly believed in her.
لقد صدقتها تقريبًا.
But her hands are already stained
لكن يديها ملطخة بالفعل
with the blood of too many innocent people.
بدماء الكثير من الأبرياء.
Mr. Liu,
السيد ليو،
I have failed you.
لقد خذلتك.
But rest assured,
ولكن كن مطمئنا،
I will give everything I have,
سأعطي كل ما لدي
to protect the Jing you cherished most.
لحماية الجينغ الذي عزيز عليك أكثر من أي شيء آخر.
♪When we first met, moonlight rippled on the water♪
♪عندما التقينا لأول مرة، كان ضوء القمر يتلألأ على الماء♪
♪Your silhouette in dreams turning back with gentle eyes♪
♪ظلك في الأحلام تعود بعيون لطيفة♪
♪A trace upon my heart, a thought quietly hidden♪
♪أثر على قلبي، فكرة مخفية بهدوء♪
♪Words almost spoken, yet our story froze in time♪
♪الكلمات كادت أن تُقال، لكن قصتنا تجمدت في الزمن♪
♪Your gaze felt familiar♪
♪نظرتك كانت مألوفة♪
♪Etched into my heart, one tear swelling into a sea♪
♪محفورة في قلبي، دمعة واحدة تتضخم في البحر♪
♪How many times have we brushed past as our fates wavered?♪
♪كم مرة مررنا بمصيرنا عندما ترددت أقدارنا؟♪
♪Only to circle back into someone's open palm♪
♪فقط للعودة إلى راحة يد شخص ما المفتوحة♪
♪That moment I saw you, spring awakened in me♪
♪في تلك اللحظة التي رأيتك فيها، أيقظ الربيع في داخلي♪
♪My heart suddenly becomes soft and tender♪
♪قلبي فجأة يصبح رقيقًا وحنونًا♪
♪Longing flowed and stirring waves of affection♪
♪تدفق الشوق وحرك أمواج المودة♪
♪Smiles and tears blurred everything in the past♪
♪الابتسامات والدموع طمس كل شيء في الماضي♪
♪The words were similar♪
♪الكلمات كانت متشابهة♪
♪With eyes closed, it felt like you were right beside me♪
♪مع عيون مغلقة، شعرت وكأنك كنت بجانبي مباشرة♪
♪That moment I saw you, spring awakened in me♪
♪في تلك اللحظة التي رأيتك فيها، أيقظ الربيع في داخلي♪
♪My heart suddenly becomes soft and tender♪
♪قلبي فجأة يصبح رقيقًا وحنونًا♪
♪Longing flowed and stirring waves of affection♪
♪تدفق الشوق وحرك أمواج المودة♪
♪Smiles and tears blurred everything in the past♪
♪الابتسامات والدموع طمس كل شيء في الماضي♪
♪The words were similar♪
♪الكلمات كانت متشابهة♪
♪With eyes closed, it felt like you were right beside me♪
♪مع عيون مغلقة، شعرت وكأنك كنت بجانبي مباشرة♪
♪After we part and meet again♪
♪بعد أن نفترق ونلتقي مرة أخرى♪
♪Your face had already changed♪
♪وجهك قد تغير بالفعل♪
♪Longing flowed and stirring waves of affection♪
♪تدفق الشوق وحرك أمواج المودة♪
♪If your words are clear♪
♪إذا كانت كلماتك واضحة♪
♪Like an image carved in the bones♪
♪مثل صورة منحوتة في العظام♪
♪It doesn't matter whose skin the soul hides underneath♪
♪لا يهم من يختبئ تحت جلد الروح♪